Guide to the James G. Harbord Papers 1902-1949 MS 1493
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: General correspondence
  - Subseries I.1: Correspondence A-Z
    - Correspondence "D", 1927 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
      Description of North Africa and the city of Algiers
    - Correspondence "D", 1925 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "D", 1924 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "D", 1923 June-December (Offsite-box 9, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "D", 1923 January-May (Offsite-box 9, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "D", 1944-1948 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "D", 1937 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "D", 1937 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "D", 1936 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "D", 1933-1935 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence "D", 1930-1932 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence "D", 1929 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 18)
      Advertising booklet for "The New Solid Porcelain De Luxe General Electric Refrigerators;" booklet on "Forestry in the Pacific Northwest;" "Bonne Annee" handmade holiday card
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1947 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
      "Dinner" folders contain invitations that Harbord received to attend various dinner engagements as well as his responses to said invitations. Includes ephemera such as invitations, dinner programs, RSVP postcards, newspaper and magazine clippings.
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1947 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1946 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1946 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1946 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1946 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1945 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1944 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1943 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1942 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1941 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1940 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1939 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1938 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1937 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1936 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1936 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1935 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1934 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1933 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1932 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1931 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1930 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1929 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1928 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1928 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1927 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1927 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1926 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1926 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1925 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1924 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1923 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1923 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1945-1947 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1941-1944 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1939-1940 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1937-1938 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1935-1936 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1933-1934 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1927-1928 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1921-1922 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1946-1947 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1944-1945 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1942-1943 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1940-1941 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1938-1939 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1936-1937 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1934-1935 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence "Dinner", 1931-1933 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence "Expense Accounts", 1928-1930 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence "Expense Accounts", 1926-1927 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence "Expense Accounts", 1923-1925 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence "F", 1945-1947 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "F", 1943-1944 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "F", 1941-1942 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "F", 1939-1940 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "F", 1937-1938 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "F", 1936 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "F", 1935 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "F", 1934 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "F", 1933 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "F", 1932 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "F", 1931 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "F", 1930 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "F", 1929 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "F", 1928 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "F", 1927 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "F", 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence "F", 1924 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence "F", 1923 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence "G", 1945-1947 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1)
      This note pertains to all "G" folders:
      Correspondents include President of the University of the South in Tennessee; I.D. Graham, Professor of Agriculture in Kansas; Harbord's third cousin Catherine Guthrie, moving to NYC from Chicago and looking for work in radio; Mr. Geary, working in Japan, who discusses his divorce in lurid detail (1933); Mr. Gooch, asking Harbord to invest in a Philippine timber company, which Harbord declines (1933); Mrs. Mary Brent Gurovtits in Manila (December 24, 1924).
      Topics include railroad development; Frank E. Gannett book on American constitution (1946) which stoked fears of communism; Harbord's Japanese servants throwing a "domestic insurrection in our own house"; tourism info for hotels and vacations; pamphlets on Japanese-American relations (1933); Sales inquiries asking Harbord to buy books and houses, which he declines; letter from an angry Red Cross nurse widow, who hadn't gotten her husband's benefits (July 1928); promotional material for Lookout Mountain estates in Georgia/Tennessee; a transcript from a court case in which Harbord testified regarding Louis T. Grant, who had been accused of embezzling 11 bottles of liquor from the government (1927); materials from the engineering-economics foundation in Beacon Hill; a letter from Floyd Gibbons at the Chicago Tribune, April 14, 1924. describing his time in Timbuktu; pamphlets from the American Committee for the Independence of Armenia decrying the Lausanne Treaty; Report, "The Senate Should Reject the Turkish Treaty;" leaflet, "The Wall Street Journal in its Beginnings" Broad & Wall 1923, with photographs and maps; pamphlet by the President of the American Federation of Labor, "From Politics to Industry", arguing against the government's role in regulating industry; additional info about pro-Armenia, anti-Turkey positions, from Jan 1923.
    - Correspondence "G", 1942-1944 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "G", 1941-1942 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "G", 1939-1940 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "G", 1937-1939 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "G", 1935-1936 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "G", 1933-1934 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "G", 1932-1933 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "G", 1930-1932 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "G", 1928-1930 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "G", 1927-1928 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "G", 1925-1927 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "G", 1924 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "G", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "H", 1946-1947 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
      This note pertains to all "H" folders:
      Topics include notifications of Harbord's death on August 20, 1947; "The Motion Picture in a World at War" from the Motion Picture Producers and Distributors of America (1942), discussing role of movies in politics and society; correspondence about a magazine meant to "teach" Filipinos to be American; Problems with Japanese servants; Coca Cola shareholders' report (1934); letters discussing Philippine Independence with Conrad Hatheway; catalogue of Interlachen Arabian Stud (horses) [Harbord bought one; Halim], with focus on breeding principles; Roosevelt Memorial Association pamphlet, 1928, from Hermann Hagedorn; a poster of a Chinese mythological figure (1927); letters from Harbord's secretary, Mary Millea, updating him to office affairs at RCA while he's out of office; letter December 14,1923 discussing Russian Relief Exposition; letter May 15th, 1943 from Bernadine Higinbotham expressing anger towards Japanese following Pearl Harbor; 1940 correspondence about the presidential election; letters discussing the Tennessee Valley Authority and the New Deal, war, Depression, etc.; 1937 "artistic lighting" catalogue from Rudolf Wendel, Inc.; Report dated December 16, 1935 on the Republican National Committee meeting with discussion of women's suffrage; letter from a civil engineer, with a proposed sketch of the New York Bay and Delaware River canal; November 14, 1928 pamphlet from Lucky Strike about how smoking is not injurious; September 5, 1944 anti-communist, pro-advertising pamphlet about lobbying government for pro-capitalist policies; 1943 pamphlet against "European collectivism" and the capital gains tax containing rhetoric about a free America that rests on unchecked capitalism; addresses by the speakers at annual meeting of the American Petroleum Institute; Oct. 22, 1937 pamphlet on how University of Oregon & Wellesley College should use their East Asian studies departments to broker peace between Japan and China, written by Commissioner to the far East for the New York World's Fair; Jan. 1936 letter from Harbord about how the U.S. should be governing the Philippines; February 2, 1937 circular on "The United States of America Incorporated Under the Laws of God and the Constitution of the United States," an anti-socialism and anti-taxation argument; January 17, 1936 pamphlet on "The Permanent Bases of Japanese Foreign Policy" from the consulate general of Japan; pamphlet on the 1936 Buenos Aires peace conference.
    - Correspondence "H", 1945-1946 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "H", 1943-1944 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "H", 1942-1943 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "H", 1941-1942 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "H", 1939-1940 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "H", 1935-1936 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "H", 1938-1939 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "H", 1937 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "H", 1936 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "H", 1934-1935 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "H", 1932-1934 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "H", 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "H", 1930-1931 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "H", 1928-1930 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "H", 1925-1927 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "H", 1925 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "H", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "H", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "H", 1945-1947 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "H", 1943-1945 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "H", 1941-1943 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "H", 1938-1940 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "H", 1936-1938 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "H", 1934-1936 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "H", 1932-1934 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "H", 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "H", 1928-1930 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "H", 1925-1928 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "H", 1923-1925 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "H", 1923-1943 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence "H", 1929-1931 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "H", 1928-1929 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "H", 1924-1928 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence "H", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence "H", 1941-1943 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence "H", 1936-1940 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence "H", 1935-1937 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence "H", 1933-1935 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence "H", 1931-1933 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence "H", 1924-1943 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence "H", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence "H", 1923-1925 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence "H", 1925-1930 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence "H", 1928-1929 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence "H", 1927-1938 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "H", 1936-1938 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence "H", 1933-1936 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, "H", 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, "H", 1932-1933 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, "I-J", 1931-1941 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 3)
      This note pertains to all "I-J" folders:
      Includes May 1931 memo from Javits & Javits law office about the I.D.C., International Development Corporation, for national corporations (U.S. and others) to invest in economically weaker countries and try to establish an "equilibrium" between them; November 1943 pamphlet from the National Safety Council on the "War on Accidents" about businesses trying to cut down on a loss of manpower; income taxes and insurance papers; September 20, 1944 anti-inflation bulletin.
    - Correspondence, "I-J", 1929-1947 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, "I-J", 1942-1947 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, "I", 1940-1941 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, "I", 1938-1939 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, "I", 1932-1937 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, "I", 1932-1946 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, "I", 1941-1945 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, "I", 1938-1941 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, "I", 1935-1937 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, "I", 1933-1935 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, "I", 1929-1933 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, "I", 1926-1929 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence "Legislation", 1910-1923 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence "Legislation", 1923-1928 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence "Insurance", 1926-1944 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1942-1944 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 4)
      This note pertains to all "K" folders
      Topics include the Manhattan Republican Flambeau Club (1939); letter November 3, 1938 from General Charles Keller discussing impact of radio and Orson Welles broadcast; letter Oct 23 1938 describing Harbord's recent trip to Philippines, Australia, Dutch East Indies, Batavia, Bandoeng; letters discussing terminal illness of Harbord's wife; photographs of Harbord's cousin Ida Knapp; issues with Japanese servants.
    - Correspondence, "K", 1942-1946 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1940-1946 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1939-1940 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1937-1939 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1936-1937 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1935-1936 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1934-1935 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1933-1934 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1932-1933 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1931-1934 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1932-1934 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, "K", 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1923-1929 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1926-1929 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1925-1927 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1938-1940 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1937-1938 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1936-1937 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1923-1942 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1942-1945 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1932-1935 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1930-1932 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1928-1930 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1927-1928 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, "L", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1946-1947 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 1)
      This note pertains to all folders in this box, MA-ME. Topics of correspondence and common correspondents include the following: Harbord's illness; Republican politics and state of the U.S.; military strategy, specifically pertaining to WWII, positioning of troops, response to Hitler; critiques of American soldier attitudes and rations; critiques of New Deal; several letters about visits and travel (people coming into NY or Harbords traveling out; scheduled meetings); letter from General Douglas MacArthur; invitation to Cuban President's daughter's wedding; golf.
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1945 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1943-1944 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1942 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1941 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1940 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1939 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1938 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1937 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1936 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1935 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1934 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1933 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1932 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1931 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1930 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1929 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1927-1928 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, "MA", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1945-1948 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1941-1944 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1938-1940 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1936-1937 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1935 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1934 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1933 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1932 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1931 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", May 1929-1930 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1927-April 1929 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 9)
      Booklets on "survey of race relations"
    - Correspondence, "MC-ME", 1923-1924 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, "Mexico and Canada (Proposed Trip)", 1943-1944 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 11)
      Harbord's birth certificate; railroad routes and schedules
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-American Legion Convention", 1937 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 12)
      Harbord's "Official Certificate of Identification" (a type of government id in lieu of passport; includes photo of Harbord); ornate certificate with official seal.
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-American Red Cross", 1945-1947 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 13)
      This note pertains to all "American Red Cross" folders. Harbord was chairman; folders include copies of addresses/speeches given and photos of 1942 speech at Red Cross Pearl Harbor Memorial.
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-American Red Cross", 1941-1944 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-American Red Cross", 1938-1940 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-American Red Cross", 1934-1937 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-American Red Cross", 1925-1933 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Army Relief Society", 1942-1948 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railway System", 1944-1947 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 19)
      Includes US Navy photographs
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railway System", 1938-1941 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railway System", 1927-1936 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 21)
      Map of Carlsbad Cavern, NM
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Aviation Investigation Committee", 1926-1927 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 22)
      Folders include copies of 2 congressional acts (for national airplane use commercially, military, etc.).
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Aviation Investigation Committee", 1925-April 1926 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Baltic Society", 1936-1946 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Baltic Society", 1924-1935 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Bankers Trust Company", 1925-1940 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Belleau Wood Memorial Association", 1931-1945 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Belleau Wood Memorial Association", 1930-1931 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Belleau Wood Memorial Association", 1927-1930 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, "Memberships-Belleau Wood Memorial Association", 1924-1927 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 7)